[Music]
the soil bacteria on Easter Island
weren't making rapy to slow down aging
but rather to slow down the growth of
its natural enemy soil fungi just like
fungi make penicillin to wipe out
competing bacteria fungi from yeast on
up like all plants and animals have mtor
genes this target of the romyen enzyme
is the universal growth regulator of
advanced life forms so while rapy
originally Drew attention as an
antifungal drug we soon learned it had
many other effects dozens of published
Studies have demonstrated that rapy by
slowing down mtor extends both the
average and maximum lifespans of
laboratory mice in fact Rapa mine
appears to be a universal anti-aging
drug extending the lifespan of all
animals and organisms tested to date the
only known drug to do so it can even
work when started in midlife the
original National Institute on Aging
interventions testing program experiment
in 2009 was delayed because the
researchers were having difficulty
keeping rapy stable in the mouse food
pelleting process it can't just be
dissolved in their drinking water
because it's fat soluble by the time
they were up and running the allotted
batch of mice were 600 days old which is
equivalent to like 60 years of age in
humans
even though the mice started the drug so
late in life their lifespans were still
extended by about 12% which could equate
to more than an added seven years of
human life initially it was debated
whether rapamycin was a true anti-aging
intervention or merely a potent
anti-cancer agent lengthening lifespans
by just preventing cancer formation mtor
signaling is hyperactive and up to 80%
of human cancers where plays a pivotal
role in sustaining tumor growth
rapamycin is used clinically to prevent
the rejection of organ transplants by
suppressing the proliferation of immune
cells that attack the new organ and A
peculiar side effect was found in a set
of 15 patients who had biopsy proven
kosi saroma a cancer that often affects
the skin all saroma skin lesions
disappeared in all patients within 3
months after starting Romy therapy the
cancer just
vanished as tour is the master regulator
of cellular growth the cancer remission
was not completely unsurprising but
subsequent rapy studies showed it can do
so much more in animal models rapy
extends Health span too rapy can
ameliorate age related declines in
cognitive function and physical
function prevent hearing
loss artery dysfunction
and tendon
stiffening regenerate the periodontal
bone that holds teeth in place and even
rejuvenate the hearts of aged mice
remarkably Health and Longevity benefits
could be achieved with intermittent or
transient dosing like getting one dose
every 5 days or for just a few months
during middle age as a dog dad I was
excited to read about the dog aging
project where people brought their
middle-aged companion canines to be
randomized a low do rapy or Placebo for
10 weeks like in the mouse studies rapy
appeared to at least partially reverse
some of the AG related heart dysfunction
without any untour side effects and
otally most of the owners of the dogs
who covertly got the WRA of mice and
reported their dogs displayed increased
activity and energy compared to only a
minority the owners of the pooches slip
the placebos it was time to try rap ay
out in hum
which I'll
cover next
[Music]